<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nsefaq on Friends of North Shore Elementary</title>
    <link>/tags/nsefaq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nsefaq on Friends of North Shore Elementary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:12:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nsefaq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What if any are the physical upgrades we can expect to see at North Shore now and in the future?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-if-any-are-the-physical-upgrades-we-can-expect-to-see-at-north-shore-now-and-in-the-future-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-if-any-are-the-physical-upgrades-we-can-expect-to-see-at-north-shore-now-and-in-the-future-/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary opened in 1927 as Coffee Pot Elementary and has all of the original buildings plus a few new ones and a few portables. In recent years, attention has come for the need to 1) Update areas of North Shore’s campus, 2) To allow our school pride to show with better views from 1st Street and 34th Avenue, and 3) To plan for growth. North Shore Elementary completed the first phase of a campus renovation in the summer of 2017 in which the school entrance (on 35th Avenue NE), front office, main hallway and the fireplace room were renovated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What kind of discipline challenges do the teachers face?  How are they encouraged to address them?  </title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-kind-of-discipline-challenges-do-the-teachers-face---how-are-they-encouraged-to-address-them---/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-kind-of-discipline-challenges-do-the-teachers-face---how-are-they-encouraged-to-address-them---/</guid>
      <description>The instances in which students are referred for excessive behavior or discipline problems in virtually nonexistent at North Shore Elementary. Our school expectations are embedded in our Guidelines for Success that form the acronym KNIGHTS (Keep Trying, Nurture our environment, Inspire cooperation, Give our best effort, Have respect, Take responsibility, Support fellow Knights). Our Guidelines for Success help teachers align their classroom rules with the school‐wide Positive Behavior System (PBS) and expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Before and After-Care Opportunities at North Shore? </title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-are-the-before-and-after-care-opportunities-at-north-shore--/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-are-the-before-and-after-care-opportunities-at-north-shore--/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of different options for Before and After-Care at North Shore. On-site there is the YMCA program that is open from 6:30am-6pm for parents and families. This program provides breakfast as well as a substantial snack after the school day, and is made up of homework and academic support, as well as extra-curricular activities. Additionally, the iClass 21st Century Learning Program is a free option for 3rd, 4th and 5th Graders that supports academic learning as well as provides extra-curricular and enrichment opportunities for students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What sort of additional academic and enrichment programming is available at North Shore Elementary?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-sort-of-additional-academic-and-enrichment-programming-is-available-at-north-shore-elementary-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-sort-of-additional-academic-and-enrichment-programming-is-available-at-north-shore-elementary-/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary offers a number of different additional educational opportunities both during and after school aimed at enhancing the learning and educational opportunities for all children. Castle Apprentice Program (CAP): CAP is a research-based program out of the University of Connecticut that focuses on giving every child exposure to gifted curriculum and project based learning. This is an opportunity for all students to explore an area of interest in a nontraditional setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the Gifted Program work at North Shore? </title>
      <link>/modules/faq/how-does-the-gifted-program-work-at-north-shore--/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/how-does-the-gifted-program-work-at-north-shore--/</guid>
      <description>Currently North Shore Elementary has 53 students enrolled in its gifted program and houses a full-time gifted Teacher. Students in the gifted program meet daily with the other students in their grade level and the gifted teacher and engage with an innovative project-based learning gifted curriculum. Unlike many other schools North Shore screens all incoming Kindergarteners for the gifted program, and then has identified students tested by the district. By doing this the school eliminates teacher and parent bias when testing for the gifted program and is better able to serve all students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does testing impact students school day and school experience?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/how-does-testing-impact-students-school-day-and-school-experience-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/how-does-testing-impact-students-school-day-and-school-experience-/</guid>
      <description>We all know there is a reputation of testing overwhelming public schools and teachers, and taking away from creative learning. There is a perception that in public schools all teachers do is teach to a test and that students are tested all the time. At North Shore we do use dand assessments to help measure student learning but we do not let it define us. All students in grades 1-5 take a MAP Assessment for in ELA (Language Arts) and Math three times a year (Fall, Winter, Spring).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does Homework look like at North Shore?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-does-homework-look-like-at-north-shore-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-does-homework-look-like-at-north-shore-/</guid>
      <description>North Shore believes in its teachers, and that they know how their students will learn and experience school best. As such, homework is a teacher-by-teacher choice. Some classrooms (most K classes) have a monthly packet that goes home with various activities to work through with your student as home time allows. Some classrooms have a weekly packet, while some other classrooms have no homework at all. There is not a top-down one size fits all approach to homework at North Shore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does North Shore offer a foreign language? </title>
      <link>/modules/faq/does-north-shore-offer-a-foreign-language--/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/does-north-shore-offer-a-foreign-language--/</guid>
      <description>Seeing and understanding the value of learning other languages, parents and administration have been working together to provide foreign language options for students. Currently, foreign language is not included in the regular day at North Shore, but Spanish is an option for an after-school enrichment once a week (see Question #10 for more information).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are art, music, PE, and recess provided at North Shore?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/how-are-art--music--pe--and-recess-provided-at-north-shore-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/how-are-art--music--pe--and-recess-provided-at-north-shore-/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary has full-time art, music, and PE teachers. All students have Art and Music once a week and PE 3-times a week. Additionally, recess is provided daily (for 20mins) and supervised by the classroom teacher. All teachers are given a bag of recess supplies (balls, hula hoops, chalk etc.) at the beginning of the year to help facilitate fun free play outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond state standards, how are teachers engaging their students?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/beyond-state-standards--how-are-teachers-engaging-their-students-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/beyond-state-standards--how-are-teachers-engaging-their-students-/</guid>
      <description>North Shore’s principal, Ms. Cooper Dawson, is passionate about student engagement and student learning. It is a priority at North Shore for teachers to understand what each of their students’ learning needs are and to ensure they are being met. While students work together through the day, they also “cluster” by ability and do individual work as well. The philosophy of Pinellas County Schools is that the only way for all kids to achieve success is to challenge and raise expectations on all students, not just a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the middle school public education options for those matriculating from NSE? </title>
      <link>/modules/faq/what-are-the-middle-school-public-education-options-for-those-matriculating-from-nse--/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/what-are-the-middle-school-public-education-options-for-those-matriculating-from-nse--/</guid>
      <description>There are many options for middle school that are available to Pinellas County Public School students and families like those who attend North Shore Elementary. The two current feeder middle schools based on geography are John Hopkins Middle School and Meadowlawn Middle School. In additional to a regular day, John Hopkins offers 2 additional programs that students may apply for as incoming 6th graders. 1) International Baccalaureate (IB Program) and 2) An award-winning Center for International Studies in the Arts and Multimedia Journalism Magnet Program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Shore Elementary is a currently a B school, and in recent history a D school. How is it a good school with a low school grade?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/north-shore-elementary-is-a-currently-a-b-school--and-in-recent-history-a-d-school.-how-is-it-a-good-school-with-a-low-school-grade-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/north-shore-elementary-is-a-currently-a-b-school--and-in-recent-history-a-d-school.-how-is-it-a-good-school-with-a-low-school-grade-/</guid>
      <description>The school grades are based purely on one standardized test given by the state each spring. In elementary school only scores from 3rd, 4th and 5th graders are included in the school grade. There are eight “components” to the elementary school grade. Four of those components are the average of scores in: 1) English Language Arts, 2) Mathematics, 3) Science and 4) Social Studies. The other four components are an expression of learning gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the School Population and Diversity?</title>
      <link>/modules/faq/schoolpopulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/faq/schoolpopulation/</guid>
      <description>North Shore is also a uniquely small school with a total of 344 enrolled students. Some other public schools that parents consider have much larger enrollments such as: Perkins- 529 students, Jamerson- 560 students, and Bay Vista- 649 students. Our neighbors at Shore Acres, a strong neighborhood school, have 645 students, just to provide some context. We do believe that North Shore’s enrollment will grow in the next few years as more neighborhood families choose the school; however, we are a small physical campus with only so much room for growth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>