<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friends of North Shore Elementary</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Friends of North Shore Elementary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>School Grade</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/aboutschoolgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/aboutschoolgrade/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unique Programs</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/coolthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/coolthings/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Students</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/specialactivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/specialactivities/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About FNSE</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>hello world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sources/testimonials/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/testimonials/a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sources/testimonials/b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/testimonials/b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Friends</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/aboutfriends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/aboutfriends/</guid>
      <description>Friends of North Shore Elementary (FNSE) was founded from sidewalk conversations in 2015. Neighbors with preschool aged children were asking themselves,&amp;ldquo;Why are families in one neighborhood attending over 10 different elementary schools instead of North Shore Elementary, our zoned school?&amp;rdquo; The interest in this idea was incredibly strong, and it was clear that many individuals wanted to support their neighborhood school. With the purpose to help bring positive focus and contribution to North Shore Elementary, FNSE incorporated as a non-profit in December 2015 and was established as a 501&amp;copy;(3) a few months later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About North Shore</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/aboutnorthshore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/aboutnorthshore/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary is a red brick school shaded by century-old oak trees, located at the north end of Coffee Pot Bayou in a quiet residential setting. It is rich in history and tradition but also is moving forward to prepare its students for the future. Come have a look at our neighborhood gem and meet the staff, schedule a tour, or learn about the new family experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>/modules/common/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>We would love to have you get engaged. There is something for everyone. Depending on your interest and availability there are a variety of ways to get involved with both North Shore Elementary and FNSE.
Become a lunch PAL, meeting with an identified student in need once a week for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Mission</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/mission/</guid>
      <description>The mission of Friends of North Shore Elementary is to partner with the school, families, and faculty to identify needs and provide sustainable resources to ensure it is a dynamic, engaging and successful public school that proudly serves families in the Northeast region of St. Petersburg. our vision is for North Shore Elementary School to be a valued community asset of the Northeast region of St. Petersburg, a key factor in attracting families and businesses to our region, and a point of pride and involvement for our neighborhood’s citizens regardless of whether they have children attending the school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight</title>
      <link>/modules/common/spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/spotlight/</guid>
      <description>This is a carousel module that showcases top things of interest at North Shore. Data is pulled from Sources-&amp;gt;Highlights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testimonial</title>
      <link>/modules/common/testimonial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/testimonial/</guid>
      <description>This is a testimonial module. All data for testimonials is pulled elsewhere. This is just to added a testimonial widget to a page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>