<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friends of North Shore Elementary</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Friends of North Shore Elementary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>School Grade</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/aboutschoolgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/aboutschoolgrade/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unique Programs</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/coolthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/coolthings/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Students</title>
      <link>/sources/highlights/specialactivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/highlights/specialactivities/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About FNSE</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>hello world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About North Shore</title>
      <link>/nse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nse/</guid>
      <description>hello world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sources/testimonials/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/testimonials/a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sources/testimonials/b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/testimonials/b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7th Hour</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/afterschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/afterschool/</guid>
      <description>At North Shore Elementary they have realized that not everything they want included in a school day fits into the 6 hour schedule. Therefore they have worked hard to bring in programming as part of the “7th Hour” or before and after-school enrichment programs. Currently there are 13 after school opportunities including: Dance, Drama, Band, Crazy 8’s, Challenge Island, Mad Science, STEM, TedEd, Girlfriends Club, Yoga, Soccer, Walking Club, and Spanish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Friends</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/aboutfriends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/aboutfriends/</guid>
      <description>Friends of North Shore Elementary (FNSE) was founded from sidewalk conversations in 2015. Neighbors with preschool aged children were asking themselves,&amp;ldquo;Why are families in one neighborhood attending over 10 different elementary schools instead of North Shore Elementary, our zoned school?&amp;rdquo; The interest in this idea was incredibly strong, and it was clear that many individuals wanted to support their neighborhood school. With the purpose to help bring positive focus and contribution to North Shore Elementary, FNSE incorporated as a non-profit in December 2015 and was established as a 501&amp;copy;(3) a few months later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About North Shore</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/aboutnorthshore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/aboutnorthshore/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary is a red brick school shaded by century-old oak trees, located at the north end of Coffee Pot Bayou in a quiet residential setting. It is rich in history and tradition but also is moving forward to prepare its students for the future. Come have a look at our neighborhood gem and meet the staff, schedule a tour, or learn about the new family experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castle Apprentice Program</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/castle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/castle/</guid>
      <description>C.A.P. is the acronym for the Castle Apprenticeship Program, previously called the “Schoolwide Enrichment Model” (SEM) that North Shore Elementary piloted in 2016. CAP is a research-based program out of the University of Connecticut that focuses on giving every child exposure to gifted curriculum and project based learning. This is an opportunity for all students to explore an area of interest in a nontraditional setting. CAP is traditionally experienced as an 8-week session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Students</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/exceptional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/exceptional/</guid>
      <description>This is a description of both ASD Programming as well as the Gifted Programming</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>/modules/common/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>We would love to have you get engaged. There is something for everyone. Depending on your interest and availability there are a variety of ways to get involved with both North Shore Elementary and FNSE.
Become a lunch PAL, meeting with an identified student in need once a week for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/coolthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/coolthings/</guid>
      <description>This is a carousel module that showcases top things of interest at North Shore. Data is pulled from Sources-&amp;gt;Highlights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Goal</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/goals/</guid>
      <description>Content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Mission</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/mission/</guid>
      <description>Our mission is to partner with North Shore Elementary in their work to ensure it is a dynamic, engaging and successful public school that proudly serves families in the Northeast region of St. Petersburg. We envision that North Shore Elementary is a dynamic, engaging, and successful school that it is a key driver for families and businesses to locate to the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent Teacher Association</title>
      <link>/modules/northshore/pta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/northshore/pta/</guid>
      <description>With the culture of the PTA being kind, inclusive, collaborative, trustworthy, available, and inspiring, general meetings are held every other month. Additionally, there are a number of committee to get involved in, Fall Festival, Turkey Trot, Educational Garden, Families Socials, to name a few, it is an easy way to get connected to the school community and have a voice in how we can better educate students.
In the coming year the PTA is looking to help support teachers and encourage participation in continuing education programs, provide scholarships and free opportunities for after school enrichments, as well as provide on-going program support for school-wide events like the One School One Book, Knight Readers, grade level field trips, and Bully Prevention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions?</title>
      <link>/modules/common/faq1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/faq1/</guid>
      <description>Am I zoned for North Shore? While the map overlay serves as a rough guide, you can check your exact address here to see if you&#39;re zoned for North Shore. Have additional questions? Head on over to our FAQ to learn more about the school, performance, teachers, events, tours and Friends of North Shore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight</title>
      <link>/modules/common/spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/spotlight/</guid>
      <description>This is a carousel module that showcases top things of interest at North Shore. Data is pulled from Sources-&amp;gt;Highlights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Informed</title>
      <link>/modules/fnse/stayintouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/fnse/stayintouch/</guid>
      <description>Our primary means of communication is through our Facebook page. Beyond that, we meet approximately once a month to discuss our roadmap. This meeting is open (?) and takes place (when / where ?). If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us. You may also find relevant information on the North Shore Elementary site or on their Twitter feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testimonial</title>
      <link>/modules/common/testimonial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/common/testimonial/</guid>
      <description>This is a testimonial module. All data for testimonials is pulled elsewhere. This is just to added a testimonial widget to a page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Choose North Shore?</title>
      <link>/modules/why/whynse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/why/whynse/</guid>
      <description>North Shore Elementary has been proudly serving students for over 90 years and is the alma mater to many of today’s leaders in St. Petersburg. It is a small school with character, compassion, diversity, and ingenuity that continues to define what successful public education should and can look like. With approximately 350 students (between 3 to 4 classes per grade) the small size of North Shore allows for all teachers and staff to know all students, not just the ones in their classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>